30 years ago, all of this was just a disused dockyard.
You had rusty cranes, empty warehouses.
Ireland's economy was was really struggling.
There was massive unemployment.
Young people were leaving in their droves to try and find jobs elsewhere.
And then the government decided to take a massive gamble,
which wasn't uncontroversial at the time.
They slashed the corporate tax rates to 12 and a half% which is way lower than you find in other developed countries and it worked.
That tax cut along with a suite of generous incentives turned a few heads among some key global players and soon the multinationals came.
Tech giants, finance firms, all wanting a foothold in Ireland.
And with them came jobs, wealth, and a brand new skyline.
&gt;&gt; Of course, it helped the island had this young English-speaking, well-educated population.
This area became known as the Silicon Docks.
And by 2024, Ireland's GDP was among the highest per capita in the world.
Although, like so many things here, there is a twist.
&gt;&gt; Hi.
Can I have Guinness?
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
This bite here represents Ireland's GDP.
It's nice and full, almost overflowing.
GDP, however, is slightly distorted by the presence of those big global players.
A lot of that money flows out of the country back to the big multinational headquarters.
And what's left is known as the GNI, which is the gross national income.
Now, this is the bit that stays in the country.
This is often seen as a better measure of Ireland's actual economy,
and it can be down by up to a third,
&gt;&gt; which means quite a lot of this that I've got to drink.
Bear with me.